Guide to the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, Local 1930 Records WAG.040
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, Local 1930 Records
1930-2007
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.)
WAG.040
15 Linear Feet in 15 record cartons.
2 websites in two archived websites.
The New York Public Library Guild Local 1930 was chartered by the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees in April 1968. The Local represents employees in all branch libraries and research libraries of the New York Public Library system, and in the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. The records consist of constitutions and by-laws, correspondence, minutes, notes, agendas, memoranda, resolutions, legal records, contract negotiations, grievance records, newspapers, publications, tapes, photographs, contact sheets, negatives and memorabilia.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of constitutions and by-laws, correspondence, minutes, notes, agendas, memoranda, resolutions, legal records, contract negotiations, grievance records, newspapers, publications, tapes, photographs, contact sheets, negatives and memorabilia. The records reflect the structure and functions of Local 1930 and the Local's relationship with District Council 37, AFSCME, other library locals, and with the AFL-CIO on the state and national levels. The bulk of the material dates from the presidency of David Beasley (1968-1975).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Local 1930 president Sally Campbell in 1979. Many of these materials were salvaged by David Beasley and local volunteers from a fire resulting from the bombing of the Local's former headquarters. The accession number associated with this gift is 1979.017. An additional donation of material was made by Local president Carol Thomas in 2008.
Websites were initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2007 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2015, these websites were migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website.
In 2017, the original URL associated with this collection, http://www.local1930.org/, became defunct. In 2018, the new URL, https://afscmeatwork.org/new-york-public-library-guild-local-1930/, was added to the web archive. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.093. In 2020, http://www.local1930.org/ was reactivated on the live web and re-added back to the web archives. The accession number associated with this website is 2021.056.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York Public Library Guild Local 1930 was chartered by the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees in April 1968. The Local represents employees in all branch libraries and research libraries of the New York Public Library system, and in the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. The bargaining unit includes professional, non-professional and technical titles.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions, except for disciplinary and termination files located in box 12. Please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Archives regarding access to these materials, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630.
Arrangement
The collection is unprocessed.
Take Down Policy
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the repository email.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Labor unions -- White collar workers -- New York (State) -- New York.; Constitutions.; Contracts; Correspondence.; Minutes (administrative records); Bylaws (administrative records); Notes.; Libraries -- New York (N.Y.); Library employees |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Publications (documents); Files (document groupings); AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.); Todd, Katherine; Campbell, Sally; New York Public Library; AFSCME. District Council 37 (New York, N.Y.); Beasley, David R., 1931-; AFSCME. Local 1930 (New York, N.Y.)
- Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 2 websites in two archived websites. (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Content Note
  The New York Public Library Guild Local 1930, formed in 1968, represents almost 2,000 clerical workers, library technical assistants, information assistants, librarians, and other titles. Members of Local 1930 are employed by the New York Public Library, by the City of New York in its branch libraries, and the libraries of mayoral departments and agencies. Capture of the website began in 2007. The website mostly was made up of letters from the executive board on staffing shortages in libraries, branch promotions, increases in library hours to 6 days a week, opening of NYPL site in Long Island City, job descriptions, budget cuts, and overdue raises. It also had an event calendar, their contract, benefits overview, press clippings, membership meetings, and information on their Women's and Lesbian and Gay Issues Committees. In 2010, the website underwent a redesign. The union focused on budget cuts, appeals to city government to increase the budget by President Valentin Colon, and calls for increased pay on work on Sundays. In 2012 the website was redesigned again and maintained the layout until 2017. This iteration of the website featured policies and procedures for library staff to avoid disciplinary action, news from DC 37 and AFSCME, benefits, contracts, the executive board, and articles about the libraries in the news. In 2018, www.local1930.org/ was not available on the live web and the website shifted to https://afscmeatwork.org/new-york-public-library-guild-local-1930/. It contained links to the DC 37 blog, resources for stewards, the collective bargaining agreement, and constitutions. In late 2020, the website redirected back to https://www.local1930.org/.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually. In 2020-2021, the website was accrued monthly.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://afscmeatwork.org/new-york-public-library-guild-local-1930/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- History and General Reference, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Constitution and By-Laws, 1974 and undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- David Beasley; New York Public Library Organizing Committee: Correspondence, Leaflets, Newsletters, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- David Beasley; Organizing Leaflets, other library locals, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- David Beasley; Correspondence, Memos, Notices, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- David Beasley; Correspondence, Memos and Notices, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- David Beasley; Correspondence and Memos, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- David Beasley; DC 37; Delegates and Executive Board Meetings, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- David Beasley; health and security plan and conference material; employee safety program questionnaire, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- David Beasley; AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930. Internal managment material: budgets, telephone directories, personnel lists, monthly growth records, constitutions., 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- David Beasley; list of mixed locals without constitutions; membership application form., 1968 + undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- David Beasley; American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees, 18th International Convention and 19th International Convention, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- David Beasley; Chart: structure of NYC Central Labor Council and its relationship to locals, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- David Beasley; New York State AFL-CIO, constitutional conventions; correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- David Beasley; Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- David Beasley; Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- David Beasley; Library directories, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- David Beasley; NYPL, internal organization and managment materials, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos, 1955-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos; B. Wilkinson, Staff Relations officer, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos; B. Wilkinson, Staff Relations officer; Memo re authorization for payroll deductions for union dues, 8/11/1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos; Winifred O'C.Luthy, Chief Of Personnel Office, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Correspondence, Memos, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Personnel Circulars, #1,3,4, 1962-1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- David Beasley; NYPL; News Bureau: Releases, Reports, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Internal Managment: charts, procedures, rules and regulations, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- David Beasley; NYPL; The Research Libraries; Discussion Paper: Conditions and needs, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Advisory Council Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Administrative memoranda, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- David Beasley; NYPL; Administrative memoranda, 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- David Beasley; NYPL; The Schomburg Collection of Black History, Literature and Arts, Inc., 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- David Beasley; NYPL; The Branch Libraries; Memoranda: #s 1-44, 1970- (Box 2, Folder 13)
- David Beasley; Local 1930, Membership; Correspondence, Memos, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- David Beasley; Local 1930; Complaints and petitions from membership, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- David Beasley; Local 1930; Internal managment material: membership resolutions, union services, welfare fund, bank accounts, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- David Beasley; Campaign for Vice President, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- David Beasley; Correspondence, memos, notes, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- David Beasley; Municipal Reference and Research Center; Proposal, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- David Beasley; New York City fiscal crisis: correspondence, articles, union publications, other print materials, memos, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- David Beasley; Correspondence, notes, memos, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- David Beasley; Notes and memos, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Katherine Todd; Correspondence, memos, notes, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Katherine Todd; NYPL; Mangment/organization: committees, reports, charts, schedules, meeting minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Katherine Todd; New York State AFL-CIO; Executive council resolutions, convention, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Katherine Todd; Membership materials: mailings, meeting minutes, committee reports; Community Labor Alliance Against the Cuts, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Katherine Todd; Styatement at budget hearings before Board of Estimate, May 4, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Katherine Todd; NYPL Association; Legislative Committee: library support legislation, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Sally Campbell; Correspondence, memos, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Sally Campbell; Meetings: Delagates & Executive Board, schedules, agendas, minutes, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Sally Campbell; American Federation of State, County & Municipal Employees, AFL-CIO; 23rd International Covention: Correspondence, Local 1930, proposals, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Sally Campbell; Complaints, correspondence, memos, newspaper clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Sally Campbell; NYPL; Local 1930; Internal organization: statistics, charts, agreements, newsletters, 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Sally Campbell; NYPL; Public works project: correspondence, memos, circular, article, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Sally Campbell; NYPL; Education fund: bibliographies, book review, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Local 1930; Vice Presidents: Virginia Jeffreys, Angeline Moscatt, Dorothy Dash; Correspondence, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Secretaries: Iris Pettiford Cox, Alan Polly, Alice Adamczyk; Correspondence, 1968-1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Local 1930; Record of membership minutes, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Local 1930; Minutes of membership meetings, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- AFSCME, DC 37; Conferences, commissions: notes, memos, annual reports, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- AFSCME, DC 37; Treasurer files: Bond reports, memos, receipts, records, tax returns, 1968-1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- AFSCME, DC 37; Treasurer files: financial reports, operating statements, 1967-1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- AFSCME, DC 37; other officers: Stewards; correspondence, 1973 & undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
- AFSCME, DC 37; NYPL; Treasurer files: Records of month dues deductions, authorization cards for NYPL, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- AFSCME, DC 37; Treasurer files: monthly reports of dues remitiances, April 1970-December 1971 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- AFSCME, DC 37; Treasurer files: monthly reports of dues remitiances, January 1973-December 1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- AFSCME, DC 37; Treasurer files: monthly reports of dues remitiances, January 1974-May 1975 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- AFSCME, DC 37; Treasurer files: monthly reports of dues remitiances, June 1975-May 1976 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- ASFCSME, DC 37; Shop Steward's manual: unemployment compensation, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; minutes of executive board, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; executive board record of meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Sally Campbell: editor of 1930 Local Line newsletter; correspondence, research materials, 1977 & undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; executive board: meetings, resolutions, correspondence, press releases, lists, statements, 1968-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- NYPL; counsel files; Brower case; court documents: briefs, memos, filings, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- State of New York, Record on Appeal: Local 1930(Beasley) v New York State Public Relations Board, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Various committees: education, standards, tutition benefits, political action, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Committees: Branch libraries, clerical advancement, staff development, cable tv, strike, organizing, THI, Library Tech, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Committees; Seniority List Committee: lists, responses, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; election committee: memos, ballots, correspondence, re-runs, vote tallies, 1973; 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- NYPL; Library support groups: Natl' Citizens Emergency Committee to Save our Libraries; Budget action committee, 1965-1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- NYPL; Library support groups: Users Association of NYC, Joint Citizens Council, Citizens' committees, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- NYPL; Local 1930; Contract negotiations; AFSCME, DC 37: contracts, press materials, leaflets, notes, 1968-1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations w/NYC: proposed contracts,negotiations, memos, statements, correspondence, 1968- (Box 4, Folder 15)
- AFSCME, Local 1930; Union report, 1930;1947 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: drafts, David Beasley, signed agreement; correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations w/NYC, NYPL: petitions, memos, ratification notices, terms, reports, revisions, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: membership questionaries & replies w/tally, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; NYPL; contract negotiations: committee ballots, correspondence, notes, proposals, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: contract proposals, drafts, correspondence, suggested changes, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: memos, case records, correspondence, notes, 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: composite lists of NYC libraries, proposals & responses, contract (copy), 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930;NYPL; working conditions negotiations: minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations:general sessions, lists of articles, signed agreements, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: document of record for negotiations, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: memos, notes, proposed plans, correspondence(David Beasley), old contract, 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; contract negotiations: different arguing positions, memos, proposals, research, city-wide contracts, correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1903; NYPL; contract negotiations: proposals, memos, correspondence, research, 1973-1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1903; Local 374 & other Locals; NYPL; contract negotiations: research, proposals,ect., 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Contract negotiations; research materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Negotiating committee; research; contracts from other locals, annual report of the Board of Estimate, 1964; 1969; 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Negotiating committee; research; contracts from other locals and unions, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Contract negotiations; Locals 1930, 374 & others; research materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Newspapers: 'The Public Employee;' contract negotions, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- The City of New York expense budget, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; NYPL; branch libraries material, 1974; undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; NYPL; contract negotiations; agreeemnts; David Beasley correspondence; executive board reports, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- New York Public Library: service review forms; David Beasley memos, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- New York Public Library; contract proposals, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- New York Public Library; proposal for Labor/Managment joint committee with notes (Box 6, Folder 14)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; NYPL; flyers, print materials, 1966-1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- New York Public Library; Local 1920 newsletter, 1968-1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- New York Public Library; union publication: 'The Local Line', 1968-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Publications regarding unions; ten articles from The Washington Post & 'Public Worker's Union to Test Political Clout in Washington', 1971 & undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Education and Research Guide, volume 1; AFSCME Dept. of Education and Research, 1965-1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Education and Research Guide, volume 2; AFSCME Dept. of Education and Research, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- AFL-CIO; New York State; publications, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Other publications: The New York Public Library, "Staff News", 1/30/1964-12/28/1972 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Other publications: The New York Public Library. "Staff News", 1/11/1974-12/26/1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Other publications: The New York Public Library, "Staff News", 1/16/1976-12/30/1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Other publications: The New York Public Library, "Staff News", 1/13/1978-12/24/1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- New York Public Library; publications: 'Library Lions' and 'The New York Public Library News', 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Other publications, The New York Public Library, Annual Reports, 1971-1977 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Other publications; American Library Association, American Libraries Handbook of Organization, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Other publications:The LARAC Reports, Library Automation and The New York Public Library and The Association of New York Libraries for Technical Services, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Other publications: Library Locals; London(Ontario) library emplouees Local 217, Canadian union of public employees; A Thirty Year History of the Union, 1945-1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Other publications: New York State Department of Labor, brochures, pamphlets re health & security benefits, 1969-1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous and Duplicates, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
- David Beasley; insurance form; Con Edison bills, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- David Beasley; New York Public Library, Fiscal crisis, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Correspondence; General, 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; Fiscal records; charts, notes, summaries, memos, 1969-1975 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- AFSCME, AFL-CIO; mailings, delagate credentials, convention materials, correspondence, 1972; undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Newspaper clippings re New York City Financial Crisis; Local 1930, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Print material: flyers, pamphlets, newsletters; budgets, potential cuts, finances, meetings, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- New York Public Library; financial statements, budgets, reports, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- AFSCME, Local 1482; Brooklyn Library Guild; Library Guild Voice, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- New York Public Library; Branch libraries contact list; charts; staff authorizations, 1967-February 1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; Authorization for payroll deductions for union dues, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930, New York Public Library Guild; executive board schedules and minutes, 1973-1978 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 8, Folder 10)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930; Sally Campbell, President; Blind and Physically handicapped legislation; background and correspondence, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Brower case; David Beasley; newspaper clippings, 'Agency Shop' statment, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- AFSCME, DC 37, Local 1930, New York Public Library; memeber materials: notices, agendas, resolutions, meetings, 1968-1971 (Box 8, Folder 13)